Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/shirinyavari-5152b9138 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Microsoft Office

Data Analysis

Statistics

Shirin Yavari

Data Scientist

Irvine, California

Summary

Experienced data scientist with a demonstrated history of working in real estate and insurance industries. Skilled in data science, predictive analytics, statistics, and machine learning. Proficiency with R, Python, SQL, and Tableau. Working experience/project completion using Artificial Neural Network, Natural Language Processing, Random Forest, and Tensorflow.

Experience

Tricon American Homes
Data Scientist
November 2017 - February 2020 (2 years 4 months)
Santa Ana, California Area

Used time series data to forecast the market growth rate index and developed

neural network predictive model to determine the optimal rental rates for single family

homes in different markets to assist the revenue management team.

Developed a predictive model to identify employees that are at risk of churning to

assist human resources team.

Developed a lead scoring analysis to assist the marketing team with lead management.

Used natural language processing (NLP) to analyze online reviews and to provide

feedback to the operation team to improve their service quality.

Automobile Club of Southern California
Data Scientist
June 2015 - November 2017 (2 years 6 months)
Costa Mesa, CA

Lead the project in automating a predictive modeling which identifies high potential abusers of the Emergency Roadside Assistance Service (ERS) in order to assist the Special Investigation Unit (SIU) in their efforts to either cancel

or warn those abusive members.

Defined project requirements and built a table in hive by extracting relevant metrics from historical data in SQL server and Teradata databases.

Saved company money and time by providing the SIU team with a predictive modeling with 86% efficiency in catching abusers using a combination of random forest and logistic regression in R.

Designed and deployed data visualizations using Tableau and completed multiple projects for Human Resources department to assist them with their training modeling, staffing, and hiring process.

Worked on the development of Dashboard reports for the Key Performance Indicators for the top management.

California State University, Fullerton Teaching Associate August 2013 - May 2015 (1 year 10 months) Fullerton, CA

Prepared and delivered lectures that engaged students and encouraged learning.

Created classwork assignments, quizzes and exams to challenge students and to increase understanding of course material.

Utilized the online programs WileyPlus and MyMathLab to create and assign homework assignments.

Held office hours to assist students outside of classroom.

Abbott Vascular Process Development Engineer June 2012 - January 2013 (8 months) Temecula, CA

Developed finished goods manufacturing process to mount the stent on a balloon catheter.

Carried characterization studies which included, study plan including design of experiments (DOEs), protocol writing, creating build packets, supervising manufacturing lines, supervising testing, analyzing data, and writing reports. Carried process optimization studies which included DOE.

Created manufacturing process documents for production operators and technicians.

TowerJazz Semiconductor

Quality Engineer
August 2010 - March 2012 (1 year 8 months)

Newport Beach, CA

Performed routine instrumental analytical methods on wafers including Vapor Phase Decomposition - Inductively Coupled Plasma Mass Spectrometry (VPD-ICPMS) analysis and Secondary-Ion Mass Spectrometry (SIMS) analysis. Participated in analytical team challenges to develop and validate new analysis methods in support of wafer manufacturing needs.

Practiced basic laboratory techniques including acid-base titration, pH measurement, specific gravity measurement, percent solid measurement, particle size distribution measurement, and laboratory safety.

Alcon Laboratories
Research And Development Engineer
July 2009 - May 2010 (11 months)
Irvine, CA

Designed, executed, and wrote reports on laboratory/clinical experiments and generated technical manuscripts in support of vitreo-retinal surgical products. Designed and performed mechanical experiments and applied knowledge of data acquisition, fluidics/ hydraulics, and video editing to compare and contrast the pressure drop along Alcon infusion cannulas against competitive offerings.

Education

California State University, Fullerton Master of Science - MS, Statistics

UC Irvine

Master of Science - MS, Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering

UC Irvine

Bachelor of Science - BS, Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering